An Inventory of the Abraham D. Sofaer Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Appearance in a TV program, letter to the editor regarding ABM Treaty, speeches before the Overseas Writers' Association, remarks on the bicentennial of the constitution, diplomacy, refugee issue, testimonies before the Senate Committee on ABM Treaty, remarks on international law and practice of the American Bar Association, and others related materials, 1987-1988 (Folder 85: 1-19)
- Miscellany, 2002 and undated (Folder 86: 1)
- Markle Foundation: Task Force on National Security in the Information Age meeting, Washington, D.C., 2002 (Folder 86: 2-3)
- Markle Foundation Task Force Report, 2002 (Folder 86: 4)
- Homeland security, 2002 (Folder 87: 1-5)
- Exhibits and bar exhibits relating to Abraham Sofaer's willingness to represent Libya in Pan Am 103 case, 1988-1994, leading to disciplinary action against him (Folder 88: 1-3)
- Transcripts of proceedings – Abraham Sofaer, respondent, 1995 (Folder 89: 1-2)
- District of Columbia Bar Committee opinions and related materials, 1996 (Folder 89: 3)
- Office of Bar Counsel, 1995-1996 (Folder 89: 4)
- District of Columbia Court of Appeals: Board on Professional Responsibility Hearing Committee – On behalf of Abraham Sofaer
  - 1996 (Folder 89: 5)
  - 1996-1997 (Folder 90: 1-4)
- Transcript of proceedings, 1997 (Folder 90: 5)
- District of Columbia Court of Appeals: Board on Professional Responsibility, 1995-2000 (Folder 91: 1-5)
- Supreme Court of the United States – Abraham Sofaer, petitioner, vs. District of Columbia Court of Appeals, undated (Folder 91: 6)
- Legal authorities, 1983-1999 (Folder 92: 1)
- Press cuttings, 1986-2003 (Folder 92: 2)
- Supreme Court of the United States – Abraham Sofaer, petitioner, vs. District of Columbia Court of Appeals, 2000 and undated (Folder 92: 3)
- Certificate required by the Rules of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals and petition instituting formal disciplinary proceedings, undated (Folder 92: 4)
- Disciplinary actions taken by the Washington, D.C. Board on professional responsibility, 1997 (Folder 92: 5)
- Appendix to Memorandum of Law on behalf of Abraham Sofaer, 2000 (Folder 92: 6)
- Prisoner transfer recommendations, 1991-1995 (Folder 93: 1)
- California earthquake policy, 1992-1998 (Folder 93: 2)
- Anti-Ballistic Missile (ABM) Treaty - Law Review articles, 1987-1999 (Folder 93: 3)
- "The ABM Treaty Dispute,", undated (Folder 93: 4)
- The ABM Treaty studies, Office of the Legal Advisor, U.S. Department of State, 1987 (Folder 93: 5)
- List of articles and speeches for Hoover Archives, 2004 (Folder 93: 6)
- New York Arbitration seminar, 2002 (Folder 94: 1)
- Camp David summit, 2000 (Folder 94: 2)
- Henry J. Hyde on war power resolution, 1995 (Folder 94: 3)
- "Prospects for Peace in the Middle East,", 1996 (Folder 94: 4)
- Middle East peace process, remarks, Baptist Church, Pennsylvania, 1998 (Folder 94: 5)
- ABM articles, 1987-2001 and undated (Folder 94: 6)
- Writings and speeches (Box 95)
  - "Liberalizing International Aviation,", 1993 (Folder 95: 1)
  - "In Praise of Competition and of Cooperation in Aerospace Technology," remarks, General Electric Jet Engine Symposium, Cincinnati, Ohio, 1993 August 16-18 (Folder 95: 2)
  - "Holy Land Numismatics – The Richest Province,", undated (Folder 95: 3)
  - Testimony, Defense Policy Panel, House of Representatives Armed Services Committee, 1988 (Folder 95: 4)
  - "Should Anyone Help Libya," The Jerusalem Report, 1993 (Folder 95: 5)
  - Article on Protocol I, letter to the editor, American Journal of International Law,", 1987 (Folder 95: 6)
  - Conference, Eighth Circuit Judicial Conference, Anti-Defamation League, St. Louis, Missouri, 1988 (Folder 95: 7)
  - "The Reagan/Shultz Legacy to the U.S.-Israel Relationship," remarks, Anti-Defamation League, New York City, 1988 (Folder 95: 8)
  - Asian-Indian American National Conference, sixth annual banquet, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1988 (Folder 95: 9)
  - "The Role of Justice," War Crimes Research Symposium, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio, 2003 (Folder 95: 10)
  - "Licenses Cross the Line," Los Angeles Times, 2003 (Folder 95: 11)
  - Stanford University Department of Music, 1995 (Folder 95: 12)
  - Selected materials for Pepperdine Law School Panel Combating Terrorism and the Impact on Civil Liberties, 2002; Commonwealth Club, 2002; and Policy Review (Folder 95: 13)
  - War Crimes in the Former Yugoslavia," World Affairs Council of Northern California, 1995 (Folder 96: 1)
  - "The Power over War," War and Responsibility: A Symposium on Congress, The President, and the Authority to Initiate Hostilities, University of Miami Law Review, 1995 (Folder 96: 2)
  - "Constitutional Issues: Distribution of Authority and Accountability," rema, Revitalizing American Federalism Conference, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, 1995 (Folder 96: 3)
  - "Crossfire," CNN television program, 1995 (Folder 96: 4)
  - "A Terrorist Defense Initiative," Wall Street Journal, 1995 (Folder 96: 5)
  - "The United Nations and the Use of Force,", undated (Folder 96: 6)
  - CLAL gathering, Remarks, 1993 (Folder 96: 7)
  - American Jewish Committee, White Plains, New York, 1993. (Folder 96: 8)
    Remarks
  - Foreign Sovereign Immunity Act (FSIA) and human rights violations, testimony, 1994 (Folder 96: 9)
  - Business Breakfast Seminar, Travel One, Baltimore, Maryland, 1994. (Folder 96: 10)
    Speech
  - "Multilateral Legal Sanctions: Sharpening an Instrument of American Foreign Policy," remarks, Allied Signal Annual Law Department Workshop, 1993 (Folder 96: 11)
  - "California and Colorado-River Water," 1997 Proceedings of the First Biennial Rosenberg International Forum on Water Policy (Folder 97: 1)
  - "Killing Abroad,", 1997. (Folder 97: 2)
    Includes 1 31/2 floppy disk
  - "New Faces of Terrorism," Ditchley Foundations Conference Group B, 1996. (Folder 97: 3)
  - "Yitzhak Rabin: Some Memories," Bar-Ilan Law Studies, 1998. (Folder 97: 4)
  - "Intellectual Capital: Business Strategy, Legal Protections and Global Competitiveness, Hoover Institution Conference, Stanford University, California, 1997 (Folder 97: 5)
  - "Foreign Investment and the Rule of Law," Russell 20-20 Meeting, California, Stanford University, 1995 (Folder 97: 6)
  - "Clinton Needs Congress on Bosnia," Wall Street Journal (Folder 97: 7)
  - 1995 (Folder 97: 8)
  - Fifteenth Anniversary Symposium on the Iran Hostage Crisis Settlement and the Iran-U.S. Claims Tribunal, New York University School of Law, 1996 (Folder 97: 9)
  - The YIVO Institute for Jewish Research, Manhattan, New York, dinner speech, 1994. (Folder 97: 10)
    Includes 5 photographic prints depicting Abraham Sofear with unidentified individuals taken during the occasion
  - Remarks, "The Role of the United Nations in the 21st Century, Ditchley Foundation Conference, Oxfordshire, England, 2001 (Folder 98: 1)
  - "Doing Justice During Wartime: Why Military Tribunals Make Sense" (with Paul R. Williams), "Combating Terrorism and the Impact on Civil Liberties," special event sponsored by Los Angeles Lawyers Division of the Federalist Society and the Pepperdine Law School Chapter of the Federalist Society, Pepperdine Law School, Los Angeles, California, 2002 (Folder 98: 2)
  - 2002 Philip C. Jessup International Law Moot Court Competition, American Society of International Law (ASIL) (Folder 98: 3)
  - Discussion and debate on "Military Tribunals between Abraham Sofaer and Robert (Bob)Wallach, sponsored by the Federalist Society and the Bar Association of San Francisco, California, 2002 (Folder 98: 4)
  - "Indian-Americans: A Political Agenda," Conference on "Indo-American Community and U.S. Policies: Heritage and Destiny," sponsored by the Navin and Pratima Doshi Chair in Indian History, University of California, Los Angeles, 2000. (Folder 98: 5)
  - "Looking Ahead: U.S. Interests, Roles and Responsibilities in the Twenty First Century," conference, sponsored by the World Affairs Council's Fifth Fourth Annual Convention, Asilomar, California, 2000. (Folder 98: 6)
  - "Moving Forward: Are the Courts Ready for the Twenty-First Century?" Collection of materials, Ninth Circuit Judicial Conference, Sun Valley, Idaho, 2000 (Folder 98: 7)
  - Participant, Conference on "Delegating Sovereignty: Constitutional and Legal Implications of U.S. Participation in Treaty Regimes," New York University School of Law, 1999. (Folder 98: 8)
    Includes 4 photographic prints depicting Abraham Sofaer and unidentified individuals
  - "Sovereignty: The Practitioners' Perspective," (with Thomas C. Heller), Conference on Problematic Sovereignty, Project on Sovereignty and Governance, Institute for International Studies, Stanford University, California, 1998 (Folder 98: 9)
  - Natan Sharansky's letter regarding the selection of the Hoover Institution Archives as the repository of Morris Pripstein's papers on his work relating to the Scientists for Sakharov, Orlov and Sharansky, 1998. (Folder 98: 10)
    Photocopy
  - Participant, Conference on The International Handling of War Crimes and Crimes against Humanity, sponsored by the Ditchley Foundation, Oxfordshire, England, 1998 (Folder 98: 11)
  - Review of Max Hilaire's International Law and US Military Intervetion in the Western Hemisphere, American Journal of International Law (AJIL), 1998 (Folder 98: 12)
  - Review of Christopher Pyle's Extradition, Politics and Human Rightsr, 1997 (Folder 98: 13)
  - Participant, The First International Conservative Congress, Washington, D.C., 1997 (Folder 98: 14)
  - "Jewish Law and the Middle East Peace Process," Loyola of Los Angeles International and Comparative Law Journal, 1999 (Folder 98: 15)
  - Abraham Sofear's rejection of a dinner invitation on behalf of Matt Fong, 1998 (Folder 98: 16)
  - Testimony, State Foreign Relations Committee (SFRC) on the War Powers Resolution, 1988 (Folder 99: 1)
  - Participant, First Circuit Conference, Massachusetts, 1988 (Folder 99: 2)
  - "The War Powers Resolution Fifteen Years Later," Herbert Lowe Myers Lecture, Temple University School of Law, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1988 (Folder 99: 3)
  - Federalist Society debate, 1988 (Folder 99: 4)
  - "Adjudication in the International Court of Justice: Progress through Realism," Coudert lecture, The Record, 1989 (Folder 99: 5)
  - "George Bush, Israel and the Middle East,", 1988 (Folder 99: 6)
  - Address, "Indian Americans and Indo-US Relations, Mumbai (Bombay), India (Folder 99: 7)
  - "Foreign Policy and the Constitution," Constitution Project Conference, American Enterprise Institute, Washington, D.C., 1989 (Folder 99: 8)
  - "Terrorism, The Law, and the National Defense," Waldemar A. Solf Lecture, Judge Advocate General's (JAG) School, Department of the Army, 1989 (Folder 99: 9)
  - Speech, Judge Advocate General (JAG), Charlottesville, Virginia, 1989 (Folder 99: 10)
- American Law Institute Sixty-Sixth Annual Meeting, Washington, D.C., 1989. (Folder 99: 11)
  Brochure
- Writings and speeches
  - Keynote speaker, the District of Columbia Bar Annual Convention, 1989 (Folder 99: 12)
  - "Priorities in Foreign Affairs," Washington Conference, New York, 1989 (Folder 99: 13)
  - Statement on The International Law and Foreign Policy: Implications of Nonconsensual Extraterritorial Law Enforcement Activities before the Subcommittee on Civil and Constitutional Rights of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States House of Representatives, 1989 (Folder 99: 14)
  - Statement on Activities Concerning the Iran-US Claims Tribunal before the Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East of the Committee on Foreign Affairs, United States House of Representatives, 1989 (Folder 99: 15)
  - "Ten Years after Camp David New Reasons for Celebration," Wall Street Journal, 1989 (Folder 99: 16)
  - "International Law and the United States Action in Panama," speech, Association of the Bar of the City of New York, 1990 (Folder 99: 17)
  - "The Legality of the United States Action in Panama," Columbia Journal of Transnational Law, 1991, and introductory speech, American Society of International Law (ASIL) Annual Meeting (Folder 99: 18)
  - Remarks, Harvard University, Massachusetts, 1990 (Folder 99: 19)
  - Speech, Yeshiva University High school dinner, 1990 (Folder 100: 1)
  - "Policy, Strategy, and International Law," participant, Symposium on low-intensity conflict (LIC), Naval War College, Rhode Island, 1990 (Folder 100: 2)
  - "Beyond Victory: The Political Dimension of Strategic Success," to be published in Naval War College Review, 1990 (Folder 100: 3)
- Iran air tragedy – Settlement proposal, 1988 (Folder 100: 4)
- Writings and speeches
  - "No Quick Fix in Iran," Washington Post, 1990 (Folder 100: 5)
  - "International Law and the United States Action in Panama," address, International Law Association, Israel branch, 1990 (Folder 100: 6)
  - "The War Powers Division," Wall Street Journal, 1990 (Folder 100: 7)
  - Address, American Jewish Committee, 1990 (Folder 100: 8)
  - Panelist, "Lawyers Role Abroad," Annual Meeting of the American College of Trial Lawyers (ACTL), San Francisco, 1990 (Folder 100: 9)
  - "Asking the UN Is Asking for Trouble," Wall Street Journal, 1990 (Folder 100: 10)
  - Letter of Invitation to visit Moscow, Modova, and Paris, 1990 (Folder 100: 11)
  - "Thinking Past the Moment," U.S. News and World Report, 1991 (Folder 100: 12)
  - Testimony before Subcommittee on International Operations regarding the Anti-Passport Boycott Act of 1991 (Folder 100: 13)
  - "Foreign Economic Sanctions," introduction to the book on sanctions, 1991 (Folder 100: 14)
  - Transcript proceedings, ABA Conference on "Strengthening the Rule of Law in the War against Drugs and Narco-Terrorism," NOVA Law Review, 1991 (Folder 100: 15)
  - Keynote address, Administrative Conference of the United States, Washington, D.C., Virginia, 1991 (Folder 100: 16)
  - "The Peace Process after the Gulf War," remarks, Convention of the American Sephardi Federation, Los Angeles, California, 1991 (Folder 100: 17)
  - Speech materials, International Association of Jewish Lawyers and Jurists, World Council meeting, Belgium, 1991 (Folder 101: 1)
- Congressional Oversight of Defense report, Center for Strategic and International Studies, Washington, D.C., 1991 (Folder 101: 2)
- Writings and speeches
  - Trip to the Hague, 1991 (Folder 101: 3)
  - "Low Intensity Conflict and the Law," Naval War College, Rhode Island, 1992 (Folder 101: 4)
  - "Inherent Powers," short version of an article, 1992 (Folder 101: 5)
  - "US Italian Relations: Issues and Outlook," conference, Institute of International Affairs, Castelgandolfo, via Bruno Buozzi, 1992 (Folder 101: 6)
  - "Jews Have the GOP all Wrong, Los Angeles Times, 1992 (Folder 101: 7)
  - "Mexico's Economic Revolution: The Legal Dimension," speech, Annual Senior Executive Forum, Conference Board, Mexico, 1993 (Folder 101: 8)
  - Advice to Iran – Dispute over the islands of Abu Musa and Greater and Lesser Tunbs, 1992 (Folder 101: 9)
- "A Smoking Gun?" William Safire, New York Times, 1992 (Folder 101: 10)
- Writings and speeches
  - Short version of an article on State Department – Entry for encyclopedia, 1993 (Folder 101: 11)
  - Meeting with Hughes, Hubbard and Reed – Agreement for joining the firm, New York, 1990. (Folder 101: 12)
    Includes 3 photographic prints depicting Abraham Sofaer and unidentified individuals, undated
  - General correspondence, vol. II, and related materials
    - 1992 January-October (Folder 101: 13)
    - 1990 December - 1991 December (Folder 102: 1)
  - Calendar
    - 1992 (Folder 102: 2)
    - 1991 (Folder 103: 1)
  - General correspondence
    - 1990 June – 1991 February (Folder 103: 2)
    - 1990 June – 1991 November (Folder 103: 3)
  - Personal correspondence, 1992 April - 1993 January (Folder 104: 1)
  - General correspondence, 1993 (Folder 104: 2)
  - OPIC Fund – Middle East Investment Fund, 1994-1998 (Folder 104: 3)
  - Dinner by Iraqi Ambassador Al-Mashat, undated (Folder 104: 4)
  - Meeting on Future of the International Court of Justice, Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1990 (Folder 104: 5)
  - "The US Department of State" - Invitation to be a contributor to the Encyclopedia of the American Presidency, 1991 (Folder 104: 6)
  - United States vs. Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO), 1988-1989 (Folder 105: 1)
  - Courtroom Television Network, Live Coverage of the International Court of Justice – Libya vs. United Kingdom, and United States Of America, 1991-1992 (Folder 105: 2)
  - Luncheon to honor the defenders of the America's Cup, 1992 (Folder 105: 3)
  - Participant, Second Circuit Judicial Conference, New York, 1992 (Folder 105: 4)
  - Speeches, Pete Wilson for Governor, 1990 (Folder 105: 5)
  - Case of Jonathan Pollard, 1998-1999 (Folder 106: 1)
  - Jonathan Pollard and Anti Defamation League, 1990-1993 (Folder 106: 2-3)
  - Air force, 1956-1959 (Folder 107: 1)
  - Amato to the opera, 1977-1978 (Folder 107: 2)
  - Letter to his son, 1974 (Folder 107: 3)
  - Magazines, 1776-1789 and a letter to John W. Dunn, 1976 (Folder 107: 4)
  - Correspondence and printed matter, 1977 (Folder 107: 5)
  - Miscellany - Correspondence and other materials (Folder 107: 6)
    - 1978.
      Includes 2 photographic prints depicting Ben and Samuel Marks, 1988
    - 1979. (Folder 108: 1)
      Includes 1 photographic print depicting a man (Abraham Sofaer?) holding a baby, 1979, and a signed framed photograph, 1979
    - 1980, and 1 photographic print depicting Abby, Zack, Suki, and David, undated (Folder 108: 2)
    - 1981 (Folder 108: 3)
    - 1982 (Folder 108: 4)
    - 1983. (Folder 108: 5)
      Includes 3 photographic prints depicting unidentified individuals and 1 print depicting Marian Schever, undated
    - 1984, letter and printed matter (Folder 108: 6)
    - 1985-1987 (Folder 109: 1-3)
    - 1988-1989. (Folder 110: 1-2)
      Includes transition materials – James Baker's, Secretary of State, ethics issue and materials relating to United States' policy towards Contras' insurgency against Nicaragua's Marxist Sandinista government
    - 1989. (Folder 111: 1-2)
      Newspapers and printed matter, 1989
- Personal correspondence and related materials, 1989. (Folder 112: 1)
  Includes 1 photographic print depicting Abraham Sofaer with two other unidentified individuals, undated
- Memoirs, 1975-1997. (Folder 112: 2)
  Includes 1 photographic print depicting Anna and David Schwartzman, undated
- Miscellany (Box 113)
  - 1990. (Folder 113: 1)
    Includes a pin, 2 photographic prints including 1 depicting Abraham Sophaer and Gao Yanping taken in the Soviet Embassy and 1 depicting him with a group of Farsi translators in an award ceremony
  - 1990-1991 (Folder 113: 2)
  - 1992. (Folder 113: 3)
    Includes Morgan Stanley and Company briefing book for trip to Israel
- Correspondence
  - 1991-1993. (Folder 113: 4)
    General correspondence
  - 1993 (Folder 113: 5)
  - 1994. (Folder 114: 1)
    Personal correspondence. Includes 1 photographic print depicting Abraham Sofaer and other unidentified individuals standing near the front door of a house, undated
  - 1988-1996 (Folder 114: 2)
  - 1996 (Folder 114: 3)
  - 1990-1997 (Folder 114: 4)
  - 1998. (Folder 115: 1)
    Includes 2 photographic prints, including 1 depicting Abraham Sofaer shaking hands with Newt Gingrich and 1 depicting the Loyola Law School Class of 1996
  - 1999 (Folder 115: 2)
  - 1999-2000. (Folder 116: 1)
    Includes an article, "Introduction" and 1 print depicting a young unidentified boy, undated
  - 2003. (Folder 116: 2)
    Includes 2 photographic prints including 1 depicting Leslie Griffin, Larry and Joanne Doherty and 1 print depicting Shannon and Dick Fairbanks and others, Washington, D.C.
  - 2000-2002. (Folder 117: 1)
    Includes 6 photographic prints, including 2 depicting Margaret and Homer (?), undated; 1 depicting the Townsend children, undated; 1 print depicting Abraham Sofaer with Lois (?) and other unidentified individuals, 2001; and 2 prints depicting a group of unidentified individuals, undated. Also includes 1 medal from the Security Technology Ventures, undated and 1 3 1/2 inch diskette, a conversation disk, undated
- Photographs
  - 1 photographic print depicting the Mustafodly family (?) on the occasion of Carnegie Hall concert, 2001, and 3 photographic prints depicting mosaic in the gallery of Fortuna Fine Arts, Ltd., 2000 (Folder 117: 2)
- Correspondence (Box 118)
  - National Jazz Museum in Harlem, 2000-2003. (Folder 118: 1-3)
    Includes 1 photographic print depicting a jazz musician; 1 CD of SIRIUS sessions, 2003; 1 CD of Willis Conover interview clips; and 1 DVD Video cassette of Fox News and CBS News, 2003
- Writings and speeches
  - "Separation of Powers and the Use of Force,", undated (Folder 118: 4)
  - "Managing the Yarkon River: Basic Principles," speech, conference on New Strategies in Financing Environmental Projects: The Case of the Yargon River, Milken Institute, Tel-Aviv University, 2002 (Folder 118: 5)
  - Address, World Affairs Council Forum on the legal entanglements surrounding Chile's General Pinochet, San Francisco, 1999 (Folder 119: 1)
  - "War Powers Panel," remarks, National Lawyers Convention, Federalist Society, Washington, D.C. (?), 1999 (Folder 119: 2)
  - "Why We're Allowed to Hit Back: The Legal Basis for Attacks on Terrorists? In a word, Self-Defense," World Presidents' Organization (WPO), remarks, San Francisco, 1999 (Folder 119: 3)
  - "United Nations and the Use of Force," personal notes and speeches, 1995 (Folder 119: 4)
  - Speech, "Indian-Americans: A Political Agenda," conference on Indo-American Community and US Politics: Heritage and Destiny, sponsored by the Navin and Pratima Doshi Chair in Indian History, University of California, Los Angeles, 2000 (Folder 119: 5)
  - Keynote speaker, Conference on The War: Theory and Practice in honor of Barry Goldwater, Arizona State University, 2000 (Folder 119: 6)
  - Panelist, Northern District of California Judicial Conference, Chaminade Conference Center, Santa Cruz, California, 2002 (Folder 119: 7)
  - Speech, Committees, Council of Foreign relations, 1993 (Folder 119: 8)
  - Personal notes and writings on Bosnia, 1995-1997 (Folder 120: 1)
  - International Court of Justice (ICJ), 2000-2002 (Folder 120: 2)
  - "Fight Evil: Seek Justice," speech, Federation of San Francisco, 2002 (Folder 120: 3)
  - Speech, The American Jewish Committee National Award Dinner, 2002 (Folder 120: 4)
  - Participant, The Role of International Law in the War Against Terrorism, World Red Cross Day, San Francisco, 2002 (Folder 120: 5)
  - Participant, Security in America: Covering Homeland Defense Conference, Sacramento, 2001 (Folder 120: 6)
  - Address to the newly sworn in American citizens, New York, 1984 (Folder 120: 7)
  - Remarks, Columbia Law Review banquet, 1983 (Folder 120: 8)
  - "Emergency Power and the Hero of New Orleans," essay, undated (Folder 120: 9)
  - "Will the Palestinians Make Peace?", 1982 (Folder 120: 10)
  - "Sentencing: Lessons from the Bible,", undated (Folder 121: 1)
  - "Jury Management in Sharon vs. Time, Inc., undated (Folder 121: 2)
  - Remarks, commencement, Yeshiva University, New York, 1980 (Folder 121: 3)
  - "The War Powers Debacle,", undated (Folder 121: 4)
  - "PCBs,", 2001 (Folder 121: 5)
  - Libya presentation, 2002 (Folder 121: 6)
- Sharon Jury materials, 1979-1985 and undated. (Folder 121: 7-11)
  Includes articles by Abraham Sofaer, "Jury Management in Sharon vs. Time, Inc.;" "Instructions on Damages;" and "Charge to the Jury: Sharon vs. Time, Inc."
- "Before the Thaw: Visual Images of Anti-Semitism in Soviet Posters, 1982-1987. (Folder 121: 12)
  19 35mm color slides and related materials, 1988-1991
- Report to the Congress, 1993 (Folder 121: 13)
- Box closed during the lifetime of Abraham D. Sofaer (Box 122)
- Miscellany (Box 123)
  - 2003-2004. (Folder 123: 1-2)